<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Examples on Helm Docs</title>
    <link>https://docs.helm.sh/examples/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Examples on Helm Docs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://docs.helm.sh/examples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://docs.helm.sh/examples/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.helm.sh/examples/readme/</guid>
      <description>Helm Examples This directory contains example charts to help you get started with chart development.
Alpine The alpine chart is very simple, and is a good starting point.
It simply deploys a single pod running Alpine Linux.
Nginx The nginx chart shows how to compose several resources into one chart, and it illustrates more complex template usage.
It deploys a deployment (which creates a replica set), a config map, and a service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://docs.helm.sh/examples/alpine/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.helm.sh/examples/alpine/readme/</guid>
      <description>Alpine: A simple Helm chart Run a single pod of Alpine Linux.
The templates/ directory contains a very simple pod resource with a couple of parameters.
The values.yaml file contains the default values for the alpine-pod.yaml template.
You can install this example using helm install docs/examples/alpine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://docs.helm.sh/examples/nginx/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.helm.sh/examples/nginx/readme/</guid>
      <description>nginx: An advanced example chart This Helm chart provides examples of some of Helm&amp;rsquo;s more powerful features.
This is not a production-grade chart. It is an example.
The chart installs a simple nginx server according to the following pattern:
 A ConfigMap is used to store the files the server will serve. (templates/configmap.yaml) A Deployment is used to create a Replica Set of nginx pods. (templates/deployment.yaml) A Service is used to create a gateway to the pods running in the replica set (templates/service.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>